# **Victor Farrell**

# **Senior Consultant**

# **QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY**

Mr. Farrell is a technical specialist with Ventera Corporation. He has over six years of experience as a full stack developer and process improvement specialist, although he has performed a broad range of other roles including development operations (DevOps) engineer, business analyst, technical writer, and scrum master. He designed and implemented a NodeJS microservice to orchestrate user management for a system of over twelve thousand users. Mr. Farrell is an optimistic, team-oriented, and sincere collaborator. Mr. Farrell's ability to communicate with high level stakeholders while delivering complex technical solutions sets Mr. Farrell apart as a valuable addition to any team.

#### **EDUCATION**

BS, Computer Science, Minor in Process Management & Consulting, The College of William & Mary

### RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Ventera Corporation

Center for Medicare & Medicaid - ESS

Senior Consultant/Full Stack Developer

Mar. 2017 - Present

Mr. Farrell is a full stack developer working on the MFT team. He writes Node JS microservices for user creation and management in coordination with Saviynt. He is working to onboard users to the new MFT solution GoAnywhere and creating new functionality through projects and workflows. Mr. Farrell is the lead Developer on PSVA (Java Swing desktop application), where he created an automated DevOps pipeline with Jenkins and GitHub.

#### **USDA - Food and Nutrition Services**

Developer

Aug. 2016 - Mar. 2017

Mr. Farrell worked on STARS site as developer. He helped with migration from Struts to AngularJS. His side projects have consisted of NodeJS, Java, Python, Django and Angular JS. He participated in the NBA hackathon as well as data analytics work for the NFL and League of Legends.

## **Genworth Financial**

Software Engineering Development Program

Jul. 2014 - Aug. 2016

Mr. Farrell participated in a two-year rotational program. His first role was with front-end web development (AngularJS and JavaScript). The second was for the iOS mobile team (Objective-C). The third was developing web services in Java and adding the Zuul gateway service to the project. The fourth was on the Big Data team where he created a Python API for accessing Health Indicators Warehouse data (Govt. data). Mr. Farrell analyzed Alzheimer's disease data and queried GNW databases to analyze claims data over time using Python. He interned in the summer of 2013 as an automation tester using HP UFT and VB script.

#### **SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Software Development Methodologies: Agile - Kanban, Scrum, Scrumban
- Application/Framework: NodeJS, Java, Python, VSCode, Jenkins, AWS, Docker, GitHub, Tableau, Django, SQL
- Project Management Tools: JIRA, Slack, Confluence, Trello, Office 365 suite, Google Workspace

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Certified ScrumMaster
- Certified SAFe 4 Practitioner

# Abrakadoodle

Consultant

Dec. 2013 - Apr. 2014

Mr. Farrell researched and advised on the adult 'paint and sip' industry. He designed the website, cost model, and outlined plan to join adult 'paint and sip' industry. http://www.abrakadoodle.com/adults/